<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?><book>
	<bookinfo>
		<title>Nashorn Object</title>
		<author>
			<personname id="pn1">
				<firstname>Zigmantas</firstname><surname>Kry&#382;ius</surname>
			</personname>
		</author>
	</bookinfo>
	<chapter id="overview"><title>Overview</title>
		<para>
			The Nashorn Object Plugin (<code>NashornObject.jar</code>) is a demo plugin showing how a Nashorn script can be rendered into
			a jEdit plugin. The main part of the plugin's function is coded as a Nashorn script.
		</para>
		<para>
			The Nashorn script <code>demo_script_object.js</code> comes with the plugin. For the plugin's start, this script should
			be placed in the subfolder <code>scripts</code> of the jEdit settings folder.
		</para>
	</chapter>
	<chapter id="use"><title>Use</title>
		<para>
			This plugin is for a (self-)educational purpose. The accompanying Nashorn script provides the Nashorn object, <code>ObjectDemo</code>, having two
			methods: <code>demoBorderPanel</code> and <code>demoScrollerPanel</code>. This script is wrapped into a jEdit Plugin.
		</para>
		<para>
			The Nashorn object, to which the script is evaluated, is cast to <code>ScriptObjectMirror</code> type and then
			<code>callMember</code> is applied. More details on the use of <code>ScriptObjectMirror</code> can be found in the official
			Nashorn documentation, or elsewhere on the Internet:
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>
			 <ulink id="oracle" type="http" url="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/8/docs/jdk/api/nashorn/jdk/nashorn/api/scripting/ScriptObjectMirror.html">https://docs.oracle.com/javase/8/docs/jdk/api/nashorn/jdk/nashorn/api/scripting/ScriptObjectMirror.html</ulink>,
			</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem><para>
			 <ulink id="tutoriala" type="http" url="https://www.javatips.net/api/jdk.nashorn.api.scripting.scriptobjectmirror">https://www.javatips.net/api/jdk.nashorn.api.scripting.scriptobjectmirror</ulink>,
			 </para>
			 </listitem>
			 <listitem><para>
			 <ulink id="tutorialb" type="http" url="http://book2s.com/java/api/jdk/nashorn/api/scripting/scriptobjectmirror/isarray-0.html">http://book2s.com/java/api/jdk/nashorn/api/scripting/scriptobjectmirror/isarray-0.html</ulink>,
			 </para>
			 </listitem>
			 <listitem><para>
			 etc.
			 </para>
			 </listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>
			Via the plugin's options, the user can change the path to the demo script or employ other Nashorn scripts and functions
			(object methods) provided by them. The plugin code can be cloned to obtain more than one Nashorn object plugin under
			different names and with different functionality.
		</para>
		<para>
			With this approach to writing a Nashorn script for a jEdit plugin, the main idea is that a method of the script's object returned something usable
			within jEdit. Then this method, with its possible arguments, is put into <code>callMember</code>.
		</para>
	</chapter>
	<chapter id="contacts"><title>Contacts</title>
		<para>
			Author's contact: <email id="email">zigmas.kr@gmail.com</email>.
		</para>
	</chapter>
</book>